Contact

sunny.mishra0389@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sunny-mishra (LinkedIn) sunnymishra.com (Blog)

Top Skills

Node.js

Java

Architectural Design

Sunny Mishra

Senior Developer | Storyteller

Bengaluru

Summary

An Engineer by qualification, a Software Developer by profession and a Storyteller by passion. I have more than a decade worth of work experience in Backend engineering and system design.

I am not using LinkedIn to find a job. Since 2018 my mission on the LinkedIn platform is to connect with junior Engineers and guide and mentor them to become more employable and productive at work. This involves one - to - one guidance over chat and publishing daily posts. These Daily LinkedIn posts contain a piece of advice or productivity ideas for software engineers, in the form of a story.

Experience

Envestnet | Yodlee India Senior Member of Technical Staff May 2016 - Present (4 years 4 months) Bangalore

- Individual contributor and responsible for customer facing product modules.
- Rewrote several APIs for launch of flagship product PFM (Personal Finance Manager).
- Written batch tool for migrating millions of existing user's data from old site to new site.
- Built engineer's productivity tools at work in spare time using Perforce Sdk.

ThoughtFocus Technologies
Team Lead | Senior Java Developer
August 2013 - May 2016 (2 years 10 months)
Bangalore

- Implemented real-time ERP integration for eCommerce product with the core product.
- Led team of 8 engineers for driving Customization efforts for eCommerce product Gensuite.
- Written batch job tools to bulk load nightly CSV feed files and Linked SQL server to DB servers.

- Implemented Export document (Pdf, Excel) functionality by integrating with Apache POI, iText and Velocity template.
- Integrated application with Auth0, an OAuth based SaaS tool for authentication and Authorization module for User entity.
- Won Best engineer award for 2015.

MindTree Ltd.

Module Lead Developer

January 2012 - August 2013 (1 year 8 months)

Bangalore

- Developed end-to-end Single page application (SPA web-app) for client
 OpenText, including UI widgets in Javascript, Spring based MVC backend, and
 MySql database design.
- Written RestFul APIs for Android app (Genapp). Redesigned backward compatibility implementation of APIs for various versions of this Mobile app.
- Won best engineer award for 2012 for the Product vertical from Client OpenText.

Oracle

Software developer August 2008 - December 2011 (3 years 5 months) Mumbai Area, India

- Implemented rules engine flow for the Citibank EMEA Netbanking product.
- Participated in architecture change to implement Internationalization of few Citibank JFP regional product modules.
- Led Netbanking Go-live Engineering Support for Citibank Turkey division. Received appreciation from Client for leading efforts, client interaction and quick turnaround.

Education

Jawaharlal Institute of Technology, MP., India Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Science

St. Karen's High School, Patna